hey guys it's benefits of a G from GE
trekker here and in this video I'm gonna
be talking about how to manage risk and
this video is gonna be response to one
of our viewers by the name of Boca Lite
who was basically asking how he might
get out of his comfort zone and start
flipping higher valued items for larger
amounts of profits now first off I want
to apologize to vocalize for taking so
long to make response video to this I
had videos lined up that I wanted to
make up until this point to help get you
guys or more the beginners kind of like
a foundation for you guys to learn off
of before I started moving on to more
advanced topics I kind of made a video
on candlestick charts which is a little
bit like an intermediate kind of topic
but in this video I'm gonna be talking
about basically how to alleviate those
concerns and manage risk so you guys can
get out of that box so I'm gonna have
three main talking points in this video
first we have diversifying investments
make your money work for you and
understanding how to read the graphs so
first off we have diversifying
investments the first thing you want to
pay attention to when you're trying to
flip any type of item you don't want to
invest all of your cash into that item
unless you're an experienced merchant in
which you know you can put all your
money in it but as for beginners though
if you're brand new to flipping then I
suggest trying to cast a wide net and
figure out which items are doing the
best at that qhorin point in time so if
you invest in one item and it's not
doing so well and all of a sudden it
starts to tank on you you still have
other items that you can bank on in
hopes to make a decent profit in which
it'll alleviate some of those losses
which will kind of keep you in the
profit zone the second the second point
I want to make is making your money work
for you
so what I mean what I mean by that is
not standing at the grand exchange and
just waiting for your items to flow
you know I often see this where users
will come into the Scourge chat and say
hey my eyes aren't instantly buying or
selling the table information is wrong
which the first first thing that did
wrong there was relying solely on the
table information and not reviewing the
graphs always always always review the
grass because prices change all the time
and those graphs are meant to help you
figure out how that item is behaving in
the market overall so the second thing
would be that you don't want to be
sitting at the grand exchange waiting
for these items to flip do other
activities in-game so if you like to do
Slayer then go ahead and do Slayer if
your ass killer than do skills that'll
make you money
the main driven point is to enjoy the
game and to enjoy the game in a way that
maybe if you want to make money make
money elsewhere and then don't just let
your money sit in the bank and just kind
of like dust away you know make the
money work for you and invest in in
different items and then maybe an hour
or two or maybe a couple days later your
flips complete and you've made an
additional profit on top of everything
else you've been doing a game so if you
like to ruin crafts and you make a good
amount of money doing that then you can
obviously kind of like allocate some of
the money into flipping make some
investments there but then go right back
to one crafting or whatever else you
want to do a game so you can make money
in two types of venues don't put all of
your effort into just flipping unless
you have like a billion GP to flip with
and all you want to do is flip but at
that point you're not really a beginner
anymore and this video isn't really for
you and then the last step is to
understand how to read the graphs from
time is how I see users coming to this
chord chat and they're still struggling
on how to actually read the graphs and
some aren't even looking at the grass
period I'm not gonna go over per se in
this video on how to read graphs i've
already
quite a few videos on that um and all
the other videos that have done
previously I've even done a live stream
recently in which you can check that out
as well
when I go over different items reviewing
the graphs himself and then reviewing my
thought process on what I'm actually
looking for in those graphs so the first
topic I brought up was diversify your
investments and if you were there for my
live stream then you're gonna notice
that some of these items here were some
of the items that I plan on investing in
and you might notice that as well that
some of the items aren't listed here
that I had planned on investing not all
of them bought and not all of them have
sold yet so this isn't a complete
picture of everything that has happened
yet but as you can tell in that one
stream I've bought one two three four
five six different items so far so I
diversified my investments I cast out a
wide net and some items didn't do so
well
I made fifty aka around 24k 30s UK but
whereas other items did a little bit
better I made around 147 K on this one
and which I bought two of these so it's
around 300 K that I'm planning to make
on Holi wraps and as well as dragon
skull dust
I made almost 500k and then an
additional like 57 K here then as you
can tell earlier in the last month I've
also done well with other types of flips
so as you can tell if you ever visited
my merchant in log here these are all
the flips that I do on the GE tracker
account so I try not to flip the same
items and everything is always different
some items are quite low whereas other
items are quite high these items here
that you guys are seeing these were
items I was trying to flip in quick
succession trying to flip them as
quickly as possible in which you can
tell that the margins were really low so
that's another thing to pay attention to
if you're
investor or merchant the timeframe in
which you try to flip the items are
gonna also determine how much of a
margin you can get on different items so
if you try flipping items very quick and
clicks accession you're not gonna do so
well and you're just gonna get some
items in here that have a low profit
whereas if you wait on an item for maybe
a couple of hours you might get half a
million on just one flip and you know
boost your sales a lot better if you're
a little bit more patient so when it
comes to flipping being patient is
definitely the endgame for this and
certainly diversify your investments so
if one investment doesn't do so well you
have other ones to Bank on and hopefully
you make absolute bank on it so instead
of talking about how to make your money
work for you I want to talk about more
on how you should allocate your actual
money in-game so you may not want to
invest all of your money in the grant
exchange and flip all of your cash
whereas you have nothing left for
supplies and gear and this isn't a very
to person to person based on your goals
so basically you want to set a specific
percentage for your investments and when
you set a specific percentage for your
investments you never want to touch that
money for anything else so say you
invest say you made 10 million in one
day and you want to take out 25 percent
of that and invest it solely for
flipping once you take out that 25
percent you never want to touch it again
for anything else except for flipping so
if you make another 10 million the next
day and your set percentage for
investments is still 25 percent and you
add an additional 25 percent cash into
your flipping then that cash stack that
you have you don't want to allocate it
for anything else it's gonna be solely
for flipping and you don't want to move
it for anything else such as gear
supplies bonds whatever you want to set
those goals specific to your skill set
whatever your account build is and
whatever your goal is these are just
examples that I have up here for you
guys in screen and again it varies from
person to person so one person might
have 25% of money made in a day for
flipping and then 75 percent of that
money for gear and supplies so let's say
you want to set up a goal for yourself
and maybe one of your goals was to get
max may take care and this is a little
bit subjective you may have a different
interpretation of what max may like it
would be maybe you wanted a saradomin
godsword in addition to having an abyss
of legend but this is just an example so
in this scenario this user is gonna be
training through Slayer to make their
money and this is gonna be their ideal
setup for training that skill so their
idea of max melee would be a badass
chest plate banlist assets amulet of
torture abyssal bludgeon in primordial
boots which comes to a total of 115
point 5 mil now the problem with new
users or just players who don't like to
flip at all or maybe who like to flip
but also want to get the best care
possible is that they allocate all of
their money to a new item or gear that
they have their eyes set on almost
immediately at the point in which they
can afford it the main concern with that
is once you buy that item and you plan
on using it now you've started off now
you're starting off with 0 GP to flip
with you now have nothing to invest your
money in at the grant exchange while
you're doing other activities in-game so
now you're just focusing on one Avenue
for money as opposed to creating two
avenues of money of sources of money in
which case you can be making money of
Slayer and making money through the
grant exchange which is the most ideal
situation so instead of trying to
allocate 25% of such
investment let's just round off this
total to let's say a hundred million
just for just to make it easy so if this
total was in fact a hundred million
let's say throughout that entire time
while you were making money you wanted
to allocate 50 percent of your profit on
any given day solely for flipping so by
the time that you reach by the time you
reach 100 million you're gonna have 100
million in the ground exchange to flip
with and it's kind of common knowledge
when you have a larger amount of cash to
work with the more money you're gonna be
able to make in the long run with that
cash by flipping so now by that point if
you kept to your goal by allocating
money to the grand exchange and not
taking that money out and investing it
on gear or supplies or whatever you've
now created a solid foundation to become
a wealthy merchant any wealthy player
in-game you've set up two avenues for
you to make money in which case you're
going to be making a significant amount
of money through the grand exchange if
you're practicing all the merging skills
properly reading graphs avoiding bubbles
you know etc etc and also making money
through the game in which you in which
ever way you like to play it so the
point is if you if you were to set a
goal for yourself like say you wanted to
get a twisted bow and your goal was to
get to allocate 50% of all your profits
ever made to flipping by the time you
can afford a twisted bow then
theoretically or hypothetically you'll
also have a billion worth in the grand
exchange flipping so then once you do
buy the twisted bow you still have money
which makes you a wealthy person in
which case you can still invest and make
money instead of solely relying on the
twisted bow to make money a sworn game
and losing that second Avenue and in the
last key point
was understanding how to read the graphs
now I'm not going to go too much in
depth in this video on how to view
graphs I've already done quite a bit of
videos on that in which you can check
out on our channel if you want to learn
more about that but I'm gonna go over
two examples in this video so for this
first item we're looking at the yearly
time frame to look at the long-haul
behavior of this item and we can tell
with this item right now it's hitting
the historic high point and we can see
right here that it's hit its peak which
is basically like a bubble when you see
an item kind of like hitting a historic
high so at this point this would be a
historic high and even at this point you
can tell that you know this item is
gonna hit a bubble soon or it's starting
to inflate like a bubble and it's gonna
pop fairly soon but it doesn't indicate
when it's going to pop or when it's
going to decline in the future it's just
kind of something to be aware of so it
kind of took some time for this item to
kind of like dip in price in the future
but it's still quite high compared to
what it was in the past so that's one on
one to pay attended to if an item is
hitting its historic high then it's
quite possible that the items gonna
decrease in the future which is
basically like a bubble and then the
second item we have is this item here
also on the yearly timeframe to give to
give ourselves the yearly overview of
how this item has behaved and we can
tell that it's hit these kind of humps
every now and then at historic lows
historic highs I mean it's gone back up
and back up down again like a roller
coaster and we can see more recently
that it's kind of mirroring what it's
behaved like again in the past so as
opposed to this item here didn't really
have that many humps for us to go off of
it had its humps in the past
like like this here and there but this
is like a new high for this item so when
it starts to hit this kind of like steep
increase it's kind of like an
abnormality there's really not much to
go off of
in terms of historically maybe something
was changed in game like an update that
made this item more valuable which is
also something to pay attention to so
you might want to look at these labels
here and if you click on them it's gonna
take you to that page to give you more
information on that so that's one thing
to pay attention to but with this item
there isn't any update in game that made
this more valuable so as just by looking
at this on the yearly timeframe I can
tell that his the historic low point
here in which in which case this is the
point in time that I would have invested
in this item in anticipation that this
item is gonna increase in price again
sometime in the future and that's
obviously not how you say a definite
guarantee but it's definitely also
possible given its behavior in the past
and now more recently we can see that
it's hitting its historic high point
again and now this is like another
bubble in which case I can expect this
item to crash again in the future so
this would be an item that I would want
to avoid
so in summary experiment with the type
of items like you're flipping don't
stick to 1/2 of an item so if you're
used to flipping high-volume items try
and flip one item that's from like the
suggested items tool or maybe highest
margins trying kind of like diversify
your investments and not stick to one
type take your time it's not it's not a
race to have the most amount of cash you
possibly can this is all about you and
your own personal growth make sure to
study the graphs so you know what you're
actually looking at be sure to divide up
your cash so if you have a long term
goal of setting yourself to get the max
meylor gear make sure you allocate some
money specifically for flipping so
you do get your melee gear you still
have money set aside for a different
Avenue for you to make money and then
the main point is to be patient you may
not make as much money as you want to on
day one but there are plenty of people
who have success stories and are doing
very well for themselves don't compare
yourself to them compare yourself to
your own growth your own historical past
and trying to prove upon your own
mistakes and learn from them
that's the middle of the video guys if
you guys liked this video be sure to
leave a like be sure to subscribe to
show your support
leave a comment down below on any type
of videos you guys want to see in the
future
good luck watching guys until next time
you